애피타이저를 12개 중
6개만 골라야 돼
The caterer sent me this list of 12
appetizers. I have to narrow it to 6.
음식? 이리 줘
Food? Oh, give me.
결혼식에 스윙 킹즈 부른다고
모니카가 얘기했어?
Did Monica mention we're trying to get
The Swing Kings to play the wedding?
언제부터 스윙 음악
좋아했어?
You're into swing music?
옛날부터야, 노래 들으러
어디든 갔다니까
I used to go all over town
listening to bands.
- 챈들러?
- 갭 광고에 나온 다음부터
-Chandler?
-Gap commercial.
- 예약했어? 전화했어?
- 할 거야
-Did you book them? Did you call?
-I will.
- 내가 전화할까?
- 자긴 자기 일이나 해
-You want me to call?
-I'll do it. You stick to your job.
- 네 일이 뭔데?
- 걸리적거리지 않는 거
-What is your job?
-Staying out of the way.
도저히 못 고르겠다
15개 다 해라
This is impossible.
Why don't you just pick all 15?
- 12개밖에 없었잖아
- 내가 3개 추가했어
-There were only 12.
-Oh, yeah, I added 3.
땅콩 버터 핑거가 뭐야?
What are "peanut-butter fingers"?
The One With
the Cheap Wedding Dress
The One With the Cheap Wedding Dress
Well, hello.
저기 좀 봐
She's cute.
귀여운데
Should we go talk to her?
가서 말 걸어볼까?
Sure. Being engaged, I'm not nervous
to talk to pretty girls anymore.
그럼 난 약혼까지 했는데
떨릴 것도 없겠지
Could you guys help me?
좀 도와주실래요?
Yeah, let me get that for you.
그럼요, 제가 들게요
-It's really heavy.
-I got it.
- 아주 무거워요
- 괜찮아요
So hi, I'm Ross,
and this is my friend, Chandler.
안녕하세요, 전 로스고
여긴 제 친구 챈들러예요
I'm Kristen.
크리스틴이에요
Hi. Are you new to the area?
크리스틴, 새로 이사왔어요?
I'd love to show you
around sometime.
괜찮다면 주변 구경
시켜주고 싶은데요
I actually just moved
from four blocks over.
네 블록밖에 안 떨어진 데서
방금 이사온건데
But this block is like another world.
하지만 이 블록은
딴 세상 같네요
Actually, it does have
a very interesting history.
여기 역사가 사실
아주 흥미롭죠
This street is the first in the city
to have an underground sewer system.
여기가 시에서 최초로
하수도가 설치된 곳이죠
Before that, sewage and waste...
그 전엔 오물과 하수가
would just flow
right down the street.
그대로 길에
철철 넘쳐 흘렀대요
Sometimes ankle-deep.
발목까지요
Smooth.
잘한다
Excuse me?
뭐라고요?
You're gonna be starving after moving.
What do you say I take you to dinner?
이사하느라 배고플 텐데
제가 저녁 대접할게요
-I'd like that.
-Great.
- 그거 좋은데요
- 좋아요
Let me take this up.
이거 올려다 줄게요
-After you.
-Oh, no. After you.
- 먼저 가세요
- 아뇨, 먼저 가요
Oh, my God!
맙소사!
Am I crazy, or does this totally go?
내가 이상한 건가
이거 잘 어울리지 않니?
Oh, my God! You look so beautiful!
와! 너 정말 예쁘다!
Thank you, Rachel.
But look at Monica!
고마워, 레이첼
하지만 모니카 좀 봐
This is it. Yeah, this is the one.
이거야, 내가 원하던 거야
I can't believe I found it.
드디어 찾았어
Wow, you look so beautiful.
If I knew you, I'd cry.
와, 너무 예쁘네요
아는 사람이면 울었을 텐데
I'm Monica Geller. Bawl like a baby.
모니카 겔러예요
실컷 우세요
I'm Megan Bailey.
메건 배일리예요
-Have you found your dress?
-These dresses are amazing...
- 원하는 드레스 찾았어요?
- 드레스는 다 예쁜데
-but I couldn't afford one.
-I can't either.
- 너무 비싸요
- 맞아요
I'm here to figure out the one I want,
then I'll get it at Kleinman's.
나도 여기선 디자인만 고르고
클라인먼즈에서 살 거예요
They're having a huge sale.
왕창 세일하거든요
-Thanks for the tip.
-When are you getting married?
- 정보 고마워요
- 언제 결혼해요?
-I'm not. I just like to try them on.
-I do the same thing.
- 안 해요, 입어보는 거 좋아해서요
- 나도 그래요
I'm just kidding.
I'm getting married July 25th.
농담이에요
7월 25일에 해요
I'm just kidding too.
나도 농담이에요
I'm getting married in December.
난 12월에 해요
-When are you getting married?
-May 15th.
- 그쪽은 언제 해요?
- 5월 15일요
It's close.
Who's your photographer?
얼마 안 남았네요
사진사는 누구예요?
-Jeffrey.
-We met with him.
- 제프리요
- 우리도 만났었어요
-Did he show you nude wedding photos?
-The Best Man? Wow!
- 누드 결혼 사진 보여주던가요?
- 남자 들러리요? 죽이죠!
I know.
I almost called off my wedding.
그러게요
결혼식 취소할 뻔 했다니까요
-Who's your band?
-My fiance wants The Swing Kings.
- 밴드는요?
- 약혼자가 스윙 킹즈 좋아해요
You're lucky. My fiance wants
the heavy metal band, Carcass.
좋겠다, 우리 약혼잔
헤비메탈 밴드, 카커스 부르재요
Is that spelled with a "C" or a "K"?
It doesn't matter, they're both great!
C로 시작해요, K로 시작해요?
하긴 둘 다 끝내주죠
Oh, don't buy that here.
여기서 사지 말아요
Now that you know what you want,
go to Kleinman's.
디자인 골랐으면
클라인먼즈에 가요
This place is so overpriced.
여긴 너무 비싸요
I own this store.
난 여기 주인이에요
So does this come
in another color, or...
혹시 이거
다른 색도 있는지...?
Hi. You moving in or moving out?
이사오는 거예요?
가는 거예요?
-Moving in.
-Can I help out?
- 오는 거예요
- 좀 도와줘요?
Okay, but be careful. The guy who was
helping before hurt his back.
좋아요, 그런데 조심해요
전에 도와주던 남잔 허리 다쳤어요
-Boyfriend?
-No.
- 남자친구요?
- 아뇨
I'm Joey.
조이예요
Kristen.
크리스틴이에요
What a beautiful name.
이름 예쁘네요
What is it again?
뭐라고 했죠?
Kristen.
크리스틴
-You live around here?
-Right down there.
- 이 동네 사세요?
- 바로 저 밑에요
Let me give you a tip.
충고 하나 할게요
Don't take a nap on this stoop.
You could wake up without shoes.
절대 여기서 자지 말아요
신발 훔쳐갈 지도 모르니까
I'll remember that.
기억해둘게요
Listen, would you like
to have dinner with me tonight?
오늘 저녁 같이 할래요?
I have plans tonight.
How about tomorrow?
선약이 있는데
내일은 어때요?
Sounds great.
Well, where does this go?
좋아요, 이거 어디로 가죠?
You look strong.
Why don't you grab one of the boxes.
힘센 거 같은데 그건
내가 들 테니 상자나 들어요
'책, 베개'
Yeah, I'll get this one.
이걸 들어야겠군
클라인먼즈
50% 세일
여기가 브룩클린이군
So this is Brooklyn?
잘 들어, 보통 한 벌에
한 사이즈밖에 없으니까
Listen up. There's only
one dress in each size.
문 열자마자 흩어져
So when they open those doors,
fan out.
이게 내가 찾는 거야
잘 봐 둬
This is what you're looking for.
Memorize it.
드레스를 찾으면
이걸 불어, 알았지?
When you locate the dress,
blow on these, all right?
세 번 부는 거야
호각 소리 들으면 뛰어 와
Three sharp blasts.
When you hear it, come running.
Here he comes!
자, 문 연다!
- 사람들이 밀어!
- 징징거리지 마!
-They're pushing!
-Don't be a baby!
- 비켜요!
- 가자!
-Out of the way!
-Let's go!
레이첼?! 가자
Rachel?! Come on!
아냐, 아니고, 아냐
No, not it. Not it. Not it.
밀지 말아요
Don't crowd me.
이거야, 이 드레스야
완벽해!
This is it! This is the dress!
It's perfect!
미안해요, 내 건데요
I'm sorry, this one's taken!
- 메건!
- 모니카!
-Megan!
-Monica!
- 왔군요!
- 그럼요
-You came!
-Yeah!
- 이건 내 드레스예요!
- 아니에요!
-This is my dress!
-No!
- 맞아요, 입은 것도 봤잖아요
- 그럼 이젠 내가 사는 걸 봐요
-You saw me wearing it.
-And now you'll see me buying it.
파렴치하긴!
You freak!
내가 안 알려줬음
여기도 몰랐을 거면서
You wouldn't even know
about this place without me.
- 나와 싸우고 싶지 않을 텐데
- 왜요, 나 잘 싸워요!
-Look, you don't want to fight me.
-Maybe I do. I'm pretty feisty!
- 갈게! 갈게!
- 이봐요!
-I'm coming! I'm coming!
-Hey!
좋아, 어떻게 하지?
Okay! Hey? Oh, what do I do?!
뭐하는 거야?
드레스 찾았어?
What are you doing?
Did you find the dress?
드레스 찾았냐고?
아니, 나 좀 구해줘
이 사람들 미쳤어
No. You gotta get me out of here.
- 모니카 찾아야지
- 내 손 잡아줘야지!
-We've gotta get Monica.
-You hold my hand!
비켜주세요!
Excuse me! Excuse me!
뛰어! 뛰어!
Go! Go! Go!
'센트럴 퍼크'
로스, 요전 날
데이트 어땠어?
How was your date the other night?
화장실에서 시작되는
마법의 여행 얘기해줬어?
Did you tell her about the magical
ride that starts with every flush?
실컷 비웃어라
또 만나자고 하던걸
Laugh all you want, but she said
she'd like to go out again.
말난 김에 전화해야겠다
In fact, I'll go call her right now.
그리고 내 친구 챈들러가
이러더라고 할게
And I'll make sure and tell her my
friend Chandler says...
어제 안 들러서 미안해
데이트했거든
Sorry I didn't stop by last
night, but I had a date.
새벽 1시엔
안 들러도 괜찮아
When it's 1:00 in the morning and you
don't come by, that's okay.
길 건너에 이사 온 아주
끝내주는 여자하고 만났어
It was with this really hot girl
who moved in across the street.
- 그래? 길 건너에?
- 그렇대도
-Right across the street?
-Yeah.
- 언제 만났어?
- 이틀 전에
-When did you meet her?
-Two days ago.
좋겠네
Excellent!
로스도 누구 만났단다
You know, Ross met somebody too.
- 야
- 어떻게 됐어?
-Hey.
-How'd it go?
토요일에 만나기로 했어
We're going out again Saturday.
그런데 만나는 남자가
또 있다고 하더라
But I found out she's
also seeing some other guy.
그래?
Really?
조이, 네가 로스 입장이라면
어떻게 하겠니?
Joe, what would you do
if you were in Ross' situation?
내가 만나는 여자도
다른 남자 만난대
I am. I'm dating this girl
who's also seeing another guy.
별로 걱정은 안 하지만
But I'm not worried about it.
당연하지, 나라면 너하고
라이벌되기 싫겠다
You shouldn't be. I wouldn't want
to be the guy who's up against you.
그 자식 운 되게 없다
I mean, that doofus is going to lose.
아주 좋은데
So this is nice.
나 정말 가기 싫거든
I wish I didn't have to go.
Believe me.
그런데 가야 돼
But I have to.
그나저나, 너희들 만나는
여자 이름이 뭐라고?
So, what's the name
of the girl you're dating?
- 크리스틴 레이
- 나 간다
-Kristen Leigh.
-Bye.
그럼 둘 중 하나는
포기해야 하는데
Well, only one of us
can keep dating her.
그렇지, 어떻게 결정하지?
Obviously. So how do we decide?
객관적으로 생각해보자
Well, now,
let's look at this objectively.
내가 만나야 된다고 생각해
I think I should date her.
아님 내가 만나던가
Or I'm the one who dates her.
재미있긴 한데
들어 봐, 내가 만날 거야
That's interesting.
But check this out. I date her.
좋아, 그렇지만
다시 생각해보면...
Okay, but to go
in another direction..
이러다 밤 새겠다
Okay. This can go on for a while.
- 그럼 뭐 좀 시키자
- 아냐, 조이
-We should order some food then.
-No, Joey.
그냥 크리스틴더러
결정하라고 하자
Look, why don't we
just let her decide, okay?
그럼 한 번씩 더
데이트한 다음
We'll each go out with her
one more time.
누굴 좋아하는지 보자
And we'll see who she likes best.
그럼 되겠네
That sounds fair.
새로 생긴 프랑스 식당에
데려가야겠다
Maybe I'll take her
to that new French restaurant.
잠깐, 데이트에 쓸 비용
상한선 정하자
Wait a second.
We have to set a spending limit.
난 그런 좋은 데
데려갈 돈 없단 말야
I can't take her
to a fancy place like that.
미안하다, 난 그런 식으로
데이트 하거든
Well, sorry.
That's what I do on dates.
그럼 나도 내 방식대로
데이트 해야겠네
Well, I guess I'll just have to do
what I do on dates.
- 좋아, 상한선 정하자
- 그래
-So let's decide on a spending limit.
-Yeah.
한 조각하고...
And a slice...
6달러 어때?
six dollars?
- 난 100달러 생각했는데
- 좋아
-I was thinking more like 100.
-Okay.
94달러 빌려줄래?
Can I borrow 94 dollars?
그러게, 티슈 좀 줄래?
I know. Can you hand me a tissue?
다이어트 콜라 떨어졌다
You're out of Diet Coke.
여보세요?
Hello?
뭐요? 뭐라고요?
What? You what?
잘 들어, 이 아가씨야!
You listen here, missy!
메건이야, 우리 결혼식날
스윙 킹즈를 예약했는데
Megan booked The Swing Kings
on the day of our wedding...
드레스 포기 안 하면
취소 안 한대
and said she'd only
give them back for the dress!
그럼 카커스
불러도 된다는 거야?
Does that mean Carcass is available?
어쩌면 좋지?
저게 딱 내 드레스란 말야
What am I gonna do? That's the dress!
That is "the" dress!
챈들러는 그 밴드를
원하고, 어쩌지?
Chandler wants the band.
What do I do?
- 챈들러를 설득해야지
- 어떻게?
-Figure out how to talk him out of it.
-How?
휴지 떨어졌어!
You're out of toilet paper!
I wanted to wish you good luck
on your date.
데이트 잘 하라고
말해주러 왔다
-Thanks.
-What time are you meeting?
- 고마워
- 몇 시에 만나?
We have reservations
at Grand Merci Bistro at 8.
그랜드 머시 비스트로에
8시에 예약했어
That's in 20 minutes.
You'd better get dressed.
20분 남았는데
어서 옷 갈아입어라
-I am dressed.
-Oh, well, good.
- 갈아입은 거야
- 그래, 잘됐네
For me.
나한테는
What's this?
Did you give yourself a facial?
이건 뭐야?
얼굴에 크림도 발라?
I have an oily T-zone.
T존 부분이 지성이란 말야
Okay, dude.
알았어
-You sent Kristen flowers?
-That's right.
- 꽃도 보냈네?
- 맞아
You spent 100 dollars.
That's the limit. You're screwed!
100달러 썼네, 한도액
다 썼으니 넌 끝장이다
I sent the flowers before
the actual date, so technically...
실제 데이트 전에
보낸 거니까
I didn't break any rules.
난 규칙 깬 거 없어
Thanks for stopping by though.
들러줘서 고맙다
That's how it's gonna be?
I can break the rules too.
그렇게 하겠단 말이지?
나도 규칙 어기지 뭐
-What are you gonna do?
-I don't know.
- 어쩔 건데?
- 그거야 모르지
-I'm not surprised.
-You won't get away with this.
- 놀랍지도 않네
- 그냥 넘어가진 않을 거야
-You don't have much choice.
-We'll see!
- 네가 어쩔건데?
- 두고보면 알아
Hey! So, just a light layer?
얇게 바르면 돼?
Yeah, just here and there.
그래, 여기하고 여기
Joey got meat sauce
on the banister again.
조이가 또 난간에
소스 묻혀놨어
Swing music is so out.
스윙 음악 한물 갔지
He's gotta be in the room
for that to work.
챈들러가 방에 있을 때
얘기해야지
What are you guys talking about?
무슨 얘기하는 거야?
We're talking about The Swing Kings...
스윙 킹즈 얘기 중인데
and whether they're
the right way to go.
정말 그 밴드로 해야 하나
해서 말야
I went to a wedding
where they had swing music...
내가 갔던 결혼식에도
스윙 음악 나왔는데
two months later
the couple divorced.
두 달 후에 그 사람들
이혼했지
I'm not saying
there's any connection here...
무슨 관계가
있다는 건 아니지만
but they did say
that's why they got divorced.
나중에 그래서
이혼했다고 하더라
But I love swing music!
난 스윙 음악 좋단 말야!
But The Swing Kings?
그렇지만 스윙 킹즈라니?
They suck so much that people die at
their concerts. They stop living.
그 밴드 너무 못 해서
콘서트에서 사람들 투신자살한대
When Monica and I went to see them,
we had fun.
모니카하고 내가 갔을 땐
재미있었단 말야
And there's another reason.
그리고 또 다른
이유도 있고
-Well, what is the other reason?
-I don't want to say.
- 그게 뭔데?
- 말하기 싫어
Well, you have to,
because maybe it's stupid.
얘기해 봐
분명히 바보같은 이유겠지
It's just, while Monica and I
were dancing to them...
모니카와 내가 그 음악에
맞춰 춤출 때
it was the first time
I knew that...
난 처음으로 깨달았어
you were the woman that I wanted
to dance all my dances with.
평생 같이 춤추고 싶은 여잔
너뿐이란 걸
Oh, crap.
미치겠네
-Our table will be ready soon.
-Oh, great.
- 금방 준비된대요
- 잘 됐네요
-Is your back feeling better?
-That's fine.
- 허리 좀 괜찮아요?
- 네, 괜찮아요
I guess the more muscles you have...
근육이 많을수록
the more they can
spasm out of control.
경련도 잘 일어나는 법이죠
-Kristen?
-Joey!
- 크리스틴?
- 조이!
-What are you doing here?
-I like this place.
- 여긴 웬일이에요?
- 내가 좋아하는 곳이에요
And technically, I'm not
breaking any rules, so...
그리고 규칙을
깨는 것도 아니니까
Well, Ross, this is Joey.
Joey, Ross.
로스, 여긴 조이
조이, 로스예요
-Hi.
-Hi. It's nice to meet you.
- 안녕하세요
- 안녕하세요, 반가워요
I used to have a friend named Joey.
나도 조이란 친구가
있었는데
I don't anymore.
이젠 친구도 아니죠
Our table will be ready
in a couple minutes.
우리 테이블
곧 준비된대요
Sure! I would love
to wait with you guys! Thanks!
물론 같이 기다려 줄게요
고마워요!
So, Joey, you look familiar.
조이, 낯이 익은데
Are you on TV or something?
혹시 TV에 나오세요?
He doesn't like to talk about it...
조이는 그 얘기하기
싫어하지만
but he's one of the stars
of Days of Our Lives.
생의 나날들에 나오는
스타예요
That's right. Don't you play a woman?
맞아요, 여자 역 하지 않나요?
A woman in a man's body.
남자 몸을 한 여자죠
Much better.
그게 훨씬 낫네요
It's funny, because you
look familiar to me too.
재미있네
그쪽도 낯이 익은데
Have you ever been married?
혹시 결혼한 적 있어요?
Yes, I have.
네, 있어요
In fact, just the other day...
사실, 요전 날
Kris and I talked about how
I've been married and have a son.
크리스틴하고 내 결혼과
아들에 대해 얘기했었죠
-Little Eric.
-That's right. Wait. No, Ben.
- 에릭이었죠
- 맞아요, 아뇨, 벤이죠
So you've just been married
the one time then?
그럼 결혼은
한 번밖에 안 했어요?
-Well...
-You've been married twice?
- 사실은...
- 결혼 두 번 했어요?
Yes. And...
네, 그리고...
another time after that.
그 다음에 한 번 더
Boy, I'm getting hungry.
배고파 죽겠네
Have you ever been so hungry
on a date...
조이는 혹시 데이트 때
너무 배고파서
that when the girl goes to the
bathroom, you eat her food?
여자가 화장실 간 사이
그 사람 음식 먹은 적 없어요?
You said the waiter ate my crab cake.
웨이터가 먹었다면서요
So, Ross, now why did
that first marriage break up?
로스, 첫 번째 결혼은
어쩌다 깨졌죠?
Was it because the woman was straight
or because she was a lesbian?
혹시 부인이
레즈비언이었기 때문인가요?
-Do you two know each other?
-No.
- 두 사람 서로 알아요?
- 아뇨
But he seems like
a guy who'd marry a woman...
로스는 왠지
레즈비언 성향이 있는 여자와
on the verge of being a lesbian
and then push her over the edge.
결혼해서 완전히 그렇게
만드는 남자일 것 같아서요
Wait a minute!
Were you on a poster for gonorrhea?
잠깐만요!
성병 포스터에 나왔죠?
Have you ever slept
in the same bed with a monkey?
원숭이와
한 침대에서 잔 적 있죠?
You leave Marcel out of this!
마르셀은 끌어들이지 마!
Fine! You ever gotten stuck
in a pair of leather pants?
좋아! 가죽 바지 입었다
곤혹치른 적 있죠?
Have you ever locked yourself
in a TV cabinet, VD-boy?
혹 TV 캐비넷에 갇힌 적
있지 않아요? 성병 보이
Monkey-lover!
원숭이 애인!
Where do you think we lost her?
어디서 나갔을까?
Probably around gonorrhea.
성병 얘기할 때였을 걸
-Hi, honey, I'm home!
-Don't come in here!
- 자기, 나 왔어!
- 들어오지 마!
Why, do you have another
boyfriend in there?
왜, 거기 다른 남자라도
있는 거야?
No. We only mess around at his place.
아니, 그 사람하고는
그 사람 집에서만 만나거든
I started it, but now it's scaring me,
so could you come out here?
내가 시작한 농담이지만
겁나는데 어서 나와줄래?
I'm wearing a wedding dress.
안 돼, 웨딩드레스 입었어
You got a wedding dress?
웨딩드레스 샀어?
-Yeah, but I'm not keeping it.
-Then why can't I see it?
- 그래, 그렇지만 돌려줘야 돼
- 그럼 봐도 되잖아
Oh. I guess you can.
그러네
But I have to return it,
so you can't like it.
그렇지만 돌려줄 거니까
마음에 들어하면 안 돼
Okay, I promise. I'll hate it.
좋아, 싫어한다고 약속하지
Wow. You look hideous.
와, 너무 끔찍하다
Really?
그래?
Yeah. That's like the most
ugliest dress I've ever seen.
그래, 그렇게
촌스런 드레스는 처음 본다
Why do you have to return it?
그런데 왜 돌려준다는 거야?
Because it doesn't really fit.
잘 안 맞아서
Oh, I booked The Swing Kings.
그나저나 스윙 킹즈 예약했어
Oh, that's great. Thanks.
그래, 잘 됐다, 고마워
But that dress is terrible.
그런데 그 드레스
정말 보기 싫다
-It makes me want to rip it off you.
-Okay.
- 찢어버리고 싶다
- 좋아
But you can't rip it.
그런데 안 돼
Well, maybe a little.
뭐, 조금만 찢어
Guys, you want to look
at the song list for the wedding?
결혼식 때 부를
노래 목록 좀 볼래?
얘들아?
Guys?
오늘 늦게 온댔잖아
I thought you'd be gone all day.
무슨 일이야?
All right, what's going on?
미안해, 아가씨들끼리 놀게
자리 비켜줄게
I'm sorry. I should probably
leave you girls alone.
실컷 웃어, 10분만 지나면
피부가 탱탱해진다고
Laugh all you want, but in 10 minutes
we'll have younger-looking skin.
모니카도 좀 발라야 돼
You know, she could use a little...
와, 잘한다! 와!
Oh, nice shot! Yeah!